Guide to the Ghassem Ghani collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- SERIES IX
  - 13. Mokhber-od-Dowleh to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Informing him of his arrival to Tehran. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 14. Fazlollah to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. A report on the situation in Meshed. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 15. Chancellor to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Ordering to have Mohammad Quli sent to Tehran. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 16. Same to same. dated 1301 A.H. Concerning the arrest of Gabbar, a Neishapur bandit. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 17. Mostafa Quli to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Concerning the sending of some of the papers of the Foreign Ministry. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 18. Chancellor to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Concerning the salary of Saheb Ekhtiar. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 19. Same to same. Concerning an officer of the guards of Roka-od-Dowleh. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 20. Habibullah from Sabzevar to Assef-od-Dowleh dated 1301 A.H. Reporting on the situation in the city. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 21. Esmail from Sabzevar to Assef-od-Dowleh, dated 1301 A.H. Congratulating him on his arrival. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 22. Fat'ali to Chancellor, dated 1293 A.H. Concerning the accounts and expenditures of the army. On the margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 23. A telegram from 8 miners to Naser-ed-Din Shah. dated 1293 A.H. Complaining of the inspector of the mines. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 24. Same to same. Same as above. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 25. Governor of Rasht to Nasir-od-Dowleh, dated 1300 A.H. Concerning the salary of Hasan Ali Mirza. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 26. A letter from Chancellor. Concerning the receipt of salary. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 27. A list of the salaries of the deceased Sepahadar's sons. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 28. A receipt of a salary. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 29. Mirza Said Khan to Naser-ed-Din Shah. Concerning Mirza Hussein Ali (Baha'u'llah) and his influence in Bagdad. Also the necessity of having him extradited. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 30. Iranian Consul General in Bagdad to Mirza Said Khan (minister of foreign affairs) Concerning Mirza Hussein Ali's arrest on exile from Bagdad. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 31. Unknown to unknown. Concerning Seyyid Hassan's cheating. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 32. Mirza Aqa Khan Nuri to (unknown) Concerning the salary of his son who was in the embassy in Paris. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 33. Notes on the discussions of Anjoman (committee) concerning the situation in Azarbaijan. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 34. A brief note concerning the original and the copy of a letter. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 35. A passport or a trade permit issued to Hadji Hasan by the Turkish officials in Bagdad. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 36. A booklet of the rules for the admittance into the Foreign Ministry, dated 1318 A.H. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 37. A telegraphic report from Khorasan, dated 1294 A.H. Concerning the propaganda of Mohammad Qaeni, a Babi. On the margin the handwriting of Naser-ed-Din Shah. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 38. Ezzat Nesa from Zanjan, dated 1292. Complaining of Nurollah, who had kidnapped her daughter. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 39. Iranian Consul in Egypt to Iranian Embassy in Istanbul, dated 28 Zi-Qada 1284 A.H. Concerning Hadji Abul Qasem who repented and had presented 300 French Louis. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 40. Same to same. dated Zi-Haja 1284 A.H. Concerning Hadji Abul Qasem and Haji Abu Taleb, two Baha's and their impedning exile. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 41. Same to same. dated 7 Zi-Haja 1284 A.H. Concerning the appointment of honorary consuls in Alexandria, Mansureh, and Tanta. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 42. Same to same. dated 12 Zi-Haja 1284 A.H. Concerning Seyyed Hussein and Hadji Allah Verchi, two Baha'is. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 43. Same to same. dated 1284 A.H. Concerning some Baha'is and the steps taken by the consul to have them exiled. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 44. Same to same. Concerning Hadji Abul Qasem and a group of Bahi who arrived from Adrianople to Mansureh. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 45. Same to same. Asking for instructions about the Bahi's mentioned above. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 46. Same to same. Concerning the Bahis and the negotiations with Ragheb Pasha to prevent them from entering Egypt. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 47. Same to same. Reporting that Ragheb Pasha had ordered all the Bahis handed over to the consulate in order that the consulate should exile them. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 48. Iranian Consul in Egypt to Iranian Embassy in Istanbul. Concerning the steps taken to arrest the Bahis. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 49. Same to same. Concerning the arrest of the Bahis and their confinemet in the consulate. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 50. Same to same. Concerning the negotiations with Raagheb Pasha for the exile of the Bahis to Saden. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 51. Same to same. Concerning the interference of the British Consulate in the arrest of the Bahis. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 52. Same to same. Concerning the exile of seven Bahis to Sudan. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 53. Same to same. Concerning Seyyed Hosein Bahi and the British Consulate. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 54. Same to same. Concerning the Bahis. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 55. A letter to Haji Mirza Aqasi. Recommending Fath Ali Khan. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 56. Summoning someone to the justice department. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 57. (contents incomprehensible) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 58. Concerning the debt of Amir Lashkar to the customs. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 59. (contents incomprehensible.) (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 60. Firuz Mirza to Amin-os-Soltan; dated 2 Jamadi-ol-sklar 1303 A.H. Concerning the appointment of Moshir-od-Dowleh as the foreign minister. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 61. Handwriting of Amin-os-Soltan on the back of Firuz Mirza's envelope. Advising (someone) to go to the King's court. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 62. Amin-os-Soltan to (unknown); dated 1307 A.H. Concerning two merchants and their claims. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 63. Amin-os-Soltan to Iranian Embassy in Istanbul dated 1310 A.H. Concerning Seyyed Jamal and his activities in Turkey. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 64. Naser-ed-Din Shah to Iranian Embassy in Istanbul; dated Gamadi-os-Sam 1281 A.H. Concerning some military decorations. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 65. Obeidollah, kurd, to Mohammad Aqa; dated 12 Rabi-of-Aval 1298 A.H. Concerning the unity of the Kurds of Iraq; on the back of the enevelope handwriting of Naser ed Din Shah (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 66. Ministry for foreign affairs to Moin-ol-Molk, Iranian Ambassador to Turkey; dated 26 Ramazan 1304 A.H. Concerning the scholarships of three Persian students in Istanbul. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 67. Unknown to unknown. Concerning a female thief. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 68. Unknown to Unknown. The same as item 67. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 69. Mirza Said Khan to (unknown); dated Jamadi-ol-Aval.1268 A.H. Concerning the new titles. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 70. Unknown to Haji Mirza Aqasi. Concerning the Turkoman raids in Bojnurd and their suppression. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 71. Abbas Mirza from Bagdad to (unknown). Concerning the prevention of the mourning ritual of the Persians in Bagdad by the Turkish officials. on the margin the handwriting of Naser ed Din. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 72. Mirza Said Khan to (unknown); dated 4 Wharram 1279 A.H. Concerning personal relations. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 73. Mohsen Khan from Teheran to (unknown). Criticizing the situation in Iran. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 74. A document concerning land dispute. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 75. A deed of ownership issued 1223 A.H. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 76. Unknown to unknown. Expressing joy at having received a medal from the shah. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 77. Unknown to Mokharõd-Dowleh. Concerning the situation in Azarbaijan and the rumors about Farmanfarma who wants to unite Azarbaijan with Turkey. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 78. Same to same. Recommending Mohammad Vali Beq. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 79. Same to same. Sending a history book written by Vazir Nezam. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 80. A letter by Abol Qasem renouncing the Bahai faith. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 81. unknown to unknown. Concerning the repair of a guest house in the vicinity of Sabzevar. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 82. Unknown to unknown. A friendly letter. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 83. Some poetry. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 84. A copy of Naser-ed-Din Shah's letter to Azed-od-Dowleh; dated Jamadi (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 85. Mohammad Ali to (unknown). Concerning the payment of a debt. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 86. A copy of a document written in Turkish and sealed by the Persian Consul in Baghdad. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 87. Hesam-os-Soltaneh to (unknown). Reassuring him about the situation in two provinces. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 88. Hesam-os-Soltaneh to Hosein Khan Sepah-Salar. Concerning the debts of Heshmat-od-Dowleh, and the condition of the army in Kurdestan and Kermanshahan. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 89. Unknown to Motavally Bashi; dated 1303 A.H. A friendly note. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 90. Iranian Consul in Egypt to Iranian Embassy in Istanbul; dated 28 Jamadi-ol-Ula 1284 A.H. Concerning Seyyed Hosein, a Bahi, who became a British citizen. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 91. King George III (1738-1820) of Great Britain, letter to Abbas Mirza, Prince Royal of Persia, announcing the birth of his niece, the future Queen Victoria. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 92. Envelope of a letter to the Queen of Germany and Prusia (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 93. Envelope of a letter to Haji Ebrahim Mujtahid Safar 1302 (Box 2, Folder 28)